A Finding Aid to the Holly Solomon Gallery Records, circa 1948-2003, in the Archives of American Art AAA.hollsolg
Archives of American Art
- Photographic Material, circa 1969-2000; Series 10; (Boxes 136-156, 194-196, 201, OV 224; 22.2 linear feet)
  - Photographs, circa 1969-2000; 10.1
    - Hutchinson, Peter, circa 1975-2000 (Box 139)
    - Jacquette, Julia, circa 1975-2000 (Box 139)
    - Jaffe/Cohen [Shirley Jaffe/Cora Cohen], circa 1975-2000 (Box 139)
    - Jaudon, Valerie, circa 1975-2000; (2 folders) (Box 139)
    - Jenney, Neil, circa 1975-2000 (Box 139)
    - Jimenez, Elise, circa 1975-2000; (Oversized material housed in box 194) (Box 139)
    - Jones, Jerry, circa 1975-2000 (Box 139)
    - Kami, Y. Z., circa 1975-2000 (Box 139)
    - Kandinsky, Wassily, circa 1975-2000 (Box 139)
    - Kirili, Alain, circa 1975-2000 (Box 140)
    - Klossowski, Pierre, circa 1975-2000 (Box 140)
    - Knowles, Christopher, circa 1975-2000 (Box 140)
    - Kushner, Robert, circa 1973-2000; (6 folders) (Box 140)
    - Lanigan-Schmidt, Thomas, circa 1975-2000; (2 folders) (Box 140)
    - Lowe, Jean, circa 1975-2000 (Box 140)
    - MacConnel, Kim, 1974-1991; (5 folders; see also oversized materials in boxes 195-196, OV 224) (Box 141)
    - MacConnel, Kim, circa 1991; (5 folders; see also oversized materials in boxes 195-196, OV 224) (Box 201)
    - Majore, Frank, circa 1975-2000 (Box 141)
    - Matta-Clark, Gordon, 1971-1989; (2 folders) (Box 141)
    - Melchert, Jim, circa 1975-2000 (Box 141)
    - Messager, Annette, circa 1975-2000 (Box 141)
    - Meyer, Melissa, circa 1975-2000 (Box 141)
    - Miller, Melissa, circa 1975-2000 (Box 141)
    - Milloff, Mark, circa 1975-2000 (Box 141)
    - Mogavero, Michael, circa 1975-2000; (2 folders) (Box 142)
    - Morisot, Berthe, circa 1975-2000 (Box 142)
    - Nahas, Nabil, circa 1975-2000 (Box 142)
    - Nonas, Richard circa 1975-2000 (Box 142)
    - Oldenburg circa 1975-2000 (Box 142)
    - Oppenheim, Dennis, circa 1975-2000 (Box 142)
    - Paik, Nam June, circa 1975-2000; (4 folders) (Box 142)
    - Passes, circa 1975-2000 (Box 142)
    - Patkin, Izhar, 1980-1990; (3 folders) (Box 142)
    - Pfaff, Judy, circa 1975-2000; (2 folders) (Box 143)
    - Phillips, Richard, circa 1975-2000 (Box 143)
    - Picasso, Pablo, circa 1975-2000 (Box 143)
    - Polke, Sigmar, 1971-1972 (Box 143)
    - Pollock, Jackson, circa 1975-2000 (Box 143)
    - Provisor, Janis, circa 1975-2000; (2 folders) (Box 143)
    - Rady, Elsa, circa 1975-2000 (Box 143)
    - Ripps, Rodney, circa 1975-2000; (3 folders) (Box 143)
    - Rothko, Mark, circa 1975-2000 (Box 143)
    - Saulson, Charles, circa 1975-2000 (Box 143)
    - Schmalix, Hubert, circa 1975-2000 (Box 143)
    - Schneeman, George, 1969-circa 2000; (2 folders) (Box 143)
    - Smith, Alexis, circa 1975-2000 (Box 143)
    - Smith, Alexis, 1973-1983; (2 folders) (Box 144)
    - Smyth, Ned, circa 1974-2000; (7 folders) (Box 144)
    - Spoldi, Aldo, circa 1975-2000 (Box 144)
    - Stettheimer, Florine, circa 1975-2000 (Box 144)
    - Stikas, Marianne, circa 1975-2000 (Box 144)
    - Stimm, Thomas, circa 1975-2000 (Box 144)
    - Sullivan, Billy, circa 1975-2000 (Box 144)
    - Weegee, circa 1975-2000 (Box 145)
    - Wegman, William, 1972-circa 2000; (4 folders) (Box 145)
    - Welch, Roger, circa 1975-2000 (Box 145)
    - Wells, Lynton, 1972-circa 2000 (Box 145)
    - Wilson, Donald Roller, circa 1975-2000; (2 folders) (Box 145)
    - Woodrow, Bill, circa 1975-2000 (Box 145)
    - Wudl, Tom, circa 1975-2000 (Box 145)
    - Wynne, Robert, circa 1975-2000 (Box 145)
    - Zakanitch, Robert, circa 1975-2000 (Box 145)
    - Zucker, Joe, circa 1975-2000 (Box 145)
    - Zucker, Joe, circa 1975-2000 (Box 146)
    - Photographs by Subject, circa 1975-2000 (Box 146)
      - Holly Solomon Gallery 1st Show, 1975 (Box 146)
      - Holly Solomon Gallery Group Shows, 1975-1989; (2 folders) (Box 146)
      - "Innovative Still Life,", 1985 (Box 146)
      - "57th Between A and D,", 1985 (Box 146)
      - "American Baroque,", circa 1988-1989 (Box 146)
      - "An Historical Over-View, Part 1", 1983 (Box 146)
      - "Part II: New Works", 1983; (2 folders) (Box 146)
      - Percent for Art program, circa 1975-2000 (Box 146)
      - "Outer Limits,", 1989 (Box 146)
      - "Aspects of Abstraction,", 1988 (Box 146)
      - Gallery Flood Damage, undated; (2 folders) (Box 146)
      - Negatives and Contact Sheets, circa 1975-2000 (Box 146)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, circa 1975-2000; (3 folders) (Box 146)
    - Jimenez, Elise, Oversized Photographs, circa 1975-2000; (See also box 139) (Box 194)
    - MacConnel, Kim, Oversized Installation Photographs, circa 1975-2000; (See also boxes 145 and 201) (Box 195)
    - MacConnel, Kim, Oversized Installation Photographs, circa 1975-2000; (See also boxes 145 and 201) (Box 196)
    - MacConnel, Kim, Oversized Installation Photographs, circa 1975-2000; (See also boxes 145 and 201) (Box OV 224)
  - Slides, circa 1975-2000; 10.2
    - Acconci, Vito, circa 1975-2000 (Box 147)
    - Adams, H.M, circa 1975-2000 (Box 147)
    - Africano, Nicholas, circa 1975-2000 (Box 147)
    - Alveng, Dag, circa 1975-2000 (Box 147)
    - Anzinger, S., circa 1975-2000 (Box 147)
    - Arp, Jean, circa 1975-2000 (Box 147)
    - Artschwager, Richard, circa 1975-2000 (Box 147)
    - Ayhens, Olive, circa 1975-2000 (Box 147)
    - Baldessari, John, circa 1975-2000 (Box 147)
    - Barry, Robert, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Bartlett, Bo, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Basel Art Fair, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Bark, Jared, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Baxter, Glen, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Beuys, Joseph, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Bickerton, A., circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Blatter, C., circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Bleckner, R., circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Boetti, Alighiero, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Borofsky, J., circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Boshier, Derek, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Bowman, John, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Brathwaite, Fred, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Burnley, Gary, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Cady, Sam, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Cage, J., circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Carlson, Mary, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Carson, Neke, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Chagall, Marc, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Chamberlain, John, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Clemente, F., circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Coe, Sue, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Cohen, Cora, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Connelly, A., circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Davis, Brad, circa 1975-2000 (Box 148)
    - Davis, Brad, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Davis, Brad and Smyth, Ned, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - DeKooning, Willem, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Dennis, Donna, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Dodge, Constance, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Downing, Thomas, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Driver, Vanzant, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Drooker, Eric, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Dufy, Raoul, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - DiRobilant, Tristano, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Eeva-Inheri, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Egleston, T., circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Eigenheer, M., circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Etkin, Suzan, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Friedman, Dan, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Fischli/Weiss, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Fontana, L., circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Forg, G., circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Garabedian, Charles, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Girouard, Tina, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Gonzalez, M., circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Goode, J., circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Graham, Dan, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Gramercy Art Fair, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Greenblatt, R.A., circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Group Show, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Haas, Michael, circa 1975-2000 (Box 149)
    - Harris, Suzanne, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Hayden, Victor, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Heilmann, Mary, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Howland, Rebecca, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - HSG interior, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Holly Solomon Gallery Construction, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Hurkmans, R., circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Hutchinson, Peter, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - IDA, Shoichi, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Jacquette, Julia, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Jaffe, S., circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Jaudon, Valerie, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Jenney, Neil, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Kami, Y.Z., circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Kandinsky, W., circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Karina, Elena, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Kempinger, Herwig, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Kessler, Jon, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Kilgour, S., circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Kirili, A., circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Klossowski, Pierre, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Knap, Jan, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Knowles, Christopher, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Kunc, Milan, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Kushner, Robert, circa 1975-2000 (Box 150)
    - Kushner, Robert, circa 1975-2000 (Box 151)
    - Landers, Sean, circa 1975-2000 (Box 151)
    - Larmee, Kevin, circa 1975-2000 (Box 151)
    - Lee, Colin Loy, circa 1975-2000 (Box 151)
    - Lichtenstein, Roy, circa 1975-2000 (Box 151)
    - Lipscomb, Mark, circa 1975-2000 (Box 151)
    - Luscher, I., circa 1975-2000 (Box 151)
    - Magauero, Michael, circa 1975-2000 (Box 151)
    - Majore, F., circa 1975-2000 (Box 151)
    - Mapplethorpe, Robert, circa 1975-2000 (Box 151)
    - Marangini, Federica, circa 1975-2000 (Box 151)
    - Matta-Clark, Gordon, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - McCail, Chad, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - McDonough, Michael, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Melchert, Jim, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Meyer, M., circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Miller, Melissa, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Milloff, Mark, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Miralda, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art Misc., circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Mitchell, J., circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Mogavero, Michael, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Moore, F., circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Morisot, Berthe, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Nahas, Nabil, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Nash, Bryan, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Nechvatal, Joseph, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Nauman, Bruce, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Oppenheim, Dennis, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Oldenburg, Claes, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Ostendarp, C., circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Otterness, T., circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Paik, Nam Jun, circa 1975-2000 (Box 152)
    - Paik, Nam Jun, circa 1975-2000 (Box 153)
    - Perrone, Jeff, circa 1975-2000 (Box 153)
    - Pfaff, Judy, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Pfaff, Judy, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Phillips, Richard, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Picasso, Pablo, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Pierson, Jack, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Polke, Sigmar, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Pollack, Barbara, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Provisor, Janis, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Perlman, C./ Rupp, C., circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Rielly, James, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Ripps, Rodney, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Rothenberg, Susan, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Rosenquist, James, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Rule, Nicolas, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Ruscha, Ed, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Salle, D., circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Schmalix, Hubert, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Schneeman George, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Schwitters, Kurt, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Simmons, Charles, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Smith, Alexis, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Smyth, Ned, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Sokolov, Joel, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - VonSompel, W., circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Spoldi, A., circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Stimm, Thomas, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Sullivan, Billy, circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Sultan, D., circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Swaits, C., circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Tobey, M., circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Tuttle, R., circa 1975-2000 (Box 154)
    - Webster, Meg, circa 1975-2000 (Box 155)
    - Wegman,William, circa 1975-2000 (Box 155)
    - Weiner, L., circa 1975-2000 (Box 155)
    - Wiener, D., circa 1975-2000 (Box 155)
    - Welch, Roger, circa 1975-2000 (Box 155)
    - Wells, Lynton, circa 1975-2000 (Box 155)
    - Wesselman, Thomas, circa 1975-2000 (Box 155)
    - Wilson, Donald Roller, circa 1975-2000 (Box 155)
    - Yarber, R., circa 1975-2000 (Box 155)
    - Zakanitch, R.S., circa 1975-2000 (Box 155)
    - Zucker, Joe, circa 1975-2000 (Box 155)
    - Misc. A-C, circa 1975-2000 (Box 155)
    - Misc. D-I, circa 1975-2000 (Box 155)
    - Misc. D-I, circa 1975-2000 (Box 156)
    - Misc. J-K, circa 1975-2000 (Box 156)
    - Misc. S-W, circa 1975-2000 (Box 156)
    - Misc. W-Z, circa 1975-2000 (Box 156)
    - Misc., circa 1975-2000 (Box 156)
    - Editions, circa 1975-2000 (Box 156)
    - Group Show, circa 1975-2000 (Box 156)
- 98 Greene Street Loft, circa 1969-1973; Series 11; (Boxes 166-169, 197-200, OV 225-227; 5.5 linear feet)
  Included in this series are sound, video, and film recordings of poetry readings, live music, art, and theatrical performances that took place from 1971-1973 at the 98 Greene Street Loft space. Unless otherwise indicated, recordings are literary readings given by the person listed, including video of the poets Joe Brainard, Jim Brodey, Michael Brownstein, Dick Gallup, Ted Greenwald, Maureen Owen, Charles Plymell, and Anne Waldman, among others. Most of the poetry readings were part of a series curated by the poet Ted Greenwald.
  In addition to readings, there are recordings of a field trip to Gordon Matta-Clark's "Splitting" house, a Christmas concert featuring Taylor Mead, and a parish Christmas party featuring the artist Thomas Lanigan-Schmidt teaching children to make tin foil angels. Also found is 98.5, Holly Solomon's collaborative documentary made with Bert Spielvogel that highlights five artists from the 98 Greene Street Loft including Charles Simonds, Ed Baynard, Susan Hall, Gordon Matta-Clark, and George Schneemann. Paper records include a few play scripts, some photographs of artists and performances, a guest book from 1971, printed material, a storyboard for a segment of 98.5, and posters used to advertise the various performances and events taking place at the loft. Performance posters are cross-referenced with the performance recordings when possible. In addition to the posters, some of the original screens used to design the posters are included. Recordings are on 13 film reels (16mm), 31 video reels (1/2 inch), and 28 sound tape reels.
  Sound, video, and film recordings are arranged in rough alphabetical order by performing artist. Where there was performance title present, it is listed first, then the artist.
  - Guest Book, 1971 (Box 166)
  - Photographs, circa 1969-1973 (Box 166)
  - Writings and Printed Materials, circa 1969-1973 (Box 166)
  - Sound, Video, and Film Recordings (Box 166)
    - Alterations, 1973 January 5; 1 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 166)
    - Alan Appel, 1972 May 12; 2 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 166)
    - David Ball, 1972 November 30; 2 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 166)
    - Ted Berrigan and Joe Brainard Reading "Train Ride", circa 1973; 1 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 166)
    - Ted Berrigan and Anne Waldman Reading "Memorial Day", circa 1973; 1 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 166)
    - The Bingo by Dick Gallup, 1973 May 19; 4 Videoreels (½ inch) Includes bound script (Box 166)
    - Joe Brainard, 1972 November 2; 2 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 166)
    - Michael Brownstein, 1973 May 17; 2 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 167)
    - Cosmic Forces a Space Opera by John Quinn and Holly Solomon, 1971 May 16; 1 sound tape reels original; 2 Film reels 16 mm; 3 sound tape reels duplicates (Box 167)
      Includes a poster advertising the performance. See box 200 for film reels and oversize folder 225 for performance poster.
    - Karen Edwards and Jim Brodey, 1973 January 18; 1 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 167)
      Also contains performances by Tammy Brodey and Bill Zaatsky
    - Kenward Elmslie reading and performance with Lee Crabtree, circa 1971; 1 sound tape reels original; 1 sound tape reels duplicate; 1 sound tape reels duplicate of excerpt 5 inch (Box 167)
      5 inch reel contains a copy of the song "Yellow Drum," which is an excerpt of the performance.
    - The Fall and Rise of Parity by Ed Baynard, 1971 April 2-4; 2 sound tape reels duplicates; 1 sound tape reels original; label reads "with Gordon Metcalf, Holly Solomon, Chuck Portz, and Pat Ast" (Box 167)
      see box 200 for performance poster
    - Footnotes to Macbeth by Holly Solomon, 1971 February 20; 1 sound tape reels includes playbill and poster (Box 167)
      See box 200 for performance poster.
    - Dick Gallup, 1971 March 15; 1 sound tape reels duplicate; 1 sound tape reels original (Box 167)
    - Dick Gallup, 1973 January 25; 2 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 167)
    - John Godfrey, 1972 November 16; 2 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 167)
    - Ted Greenwald, 1973 May; 2 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 167)
    - Ted Greenwald, circa 1971; 1 sound tape reels duplicate; 1 sound tape reels original (Box 167)
      Box label reads "Ted Greenwald and Gordon Matta," but reading is mostly Ted Greenwald. Matta may make an appearance in a nonsense dialogue beginning around 11 minutes into recording.
    - Andy Grundberg, 1972 December 14; 2 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 168)
    - Mammoth Benefit for Adventures in Poetry, 1971 April 12; 1 sound tape reels duplicate; 1 sound tape reels includes poster original (Box 168)
      See box 200 for performance poster for list of artists.
    - Gordon Matta-Clark, Field Trip to "Splitting" House, circa 1974; 1 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 168)
    - Taylor Mead Performance at Christmas Party, 1972 December 19; 2 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 168)
      Tape also contains performances by Wade County and the Country Squires, and Paul Ambrose. See oversize folder 226 for performance poster.
    - Taylor Mead, 1971 January 29; 1 sound tape reels duplicate; 1 sound tape reels originla (Box 168)
    - Music Consort Group, circa 1971; 3 sound tape reels (Box 168)
    - Now I In You Without A Body Move by George Herbert, circa 1971; 1 sound tape reels (Box 168)
    - Maureen Owen, 1972 November 9; 2 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 168)
    - Poets Group, 1972 December 21; 2 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 168)
      Readers include Michael Brownstein, Steve Katz, Maureen Owen, Dick Gallup, Joe Brainard, Peter Schejldahl, Lewis Warsh, Anne Waldman, Larry Fagin, and Ron Padgett.
    - Peter Schjeldahl, circa 1971; 1 sound tape reels original; 1 sound tape reels incomplete duplicate (Box 168)
    - There Aren't Any by Harris Freedman, circa 1971; 1 sound tape reels original; 1 sound tape reels duplicate (Box 169)
    - Anne Waldman, 1973 April 26; 2 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 169)
    - Rebecca Wright, 1972 December 12; 2 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 169)
    - Unidentified Figure Skaters, circa 1971; 1 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 169)
    - Unidentified Musical Recording, circa 1971; 1 sound tape reels Label reads "You are old, Father William", "Alice", "organ, base, drums, woodwind, moog synthesizer" (Box 169)
    - Unidentified Theater Rehearsal, circa 1971; 2 Videoreels (½ inch) (Box 169)
    - 98.5 by Holly Solomon and Bert Spielvogel, 1972; 2 Film reels original print 16 mm; 4 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) duplicates; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) duplicates; 8 Film reels duplicate prints and partial prints; 1 Film reels outtakes from "Claypits" segment (Box 169)
      Five part documentary with segments titled "Claypits" by Charles Simonds, "Interview" with Ed Baynard, "Windows" by Susan Hall, "Freshkill" by Gordon Matta-Clark, and "Portrait" by George Schneeman. See box 200 for partial storyboard of Susan Hall's "Windows;" film reels moved to boxes 197-200.
  - Sound, Video, and Film, 98.5 by Holly Solomon and Bert Spielvogel (Box 197-199)
    9 of 11 film reels from Box 169, including 3 complete prints of 2 reels each, 1 additional print of reel 2, 1 partial print of reel 1, and a reel of outtakes from Charles Simonds "Claypits."
  - Sound, Video, and Film, 98.5 by Holly Solomon and Bert Spielvogel (Box 200)
    2 of 11 film reels from Box 169, including 1 reel containing "Claypits" segment and film credits, and a second reel containing "Claypits" only
  - Sound, Video, and Film, Cosmic Forces a Space Opera by John Quinn and Holly Solomon, 2 Film reels (Box 200)
  - Oversized Posters and Fliers, circa 1969-1973 (Box 200)
  - Posters, circa 1969-1973 (Box OV 225-227)
- Holly Solomon Personal Papers, circa 1948-2002; Series 12; (Boxes 170-182, 194; 13.1 linear feet)
  Holly Solomon's personal papers consist of biographical documents, correspondence, memorabilia, printed material, motion picture film, and photographs collected by Holly Solomon throughout her life. The earliest materials include high school mementos and both her high school and college yearbooks, while later items include notes and cards from friends and artists she represented at her gallery. The boxes of personal correspondence, memorabilia and photographs are not sorted or organized any particular order. Included are postcards, telegrams, letters, photographs of friends and family, invitations, and event fliers.
  Motion picture films include one short reel of black and white 16mm and a color Super 8mm (400 ft.) of Holly Solomon and others who are unidentified. Also found are three film reels (16mm, color) of a golfer. This series also includes legal documents regarding Solomon's 1990 divorce and a collection of printed material, mostly magazines and newspapers covering her accomplishments. The printed materials range from the 1950s through her death in 2002. The guest books from her 2002 memorial service at the Guggenheim are also included.
  - Motion Picture Film (Box 170)
    - Footage of Holly Solomon, circa 1960-1979; (2 film reels: 1 16mm, 1 Super 8mm) (Box 170)
    - Lloyd's Golf Swing, 1953; (3 film reels: 16mm) (Box 170)
  - Correspondence, Memorabilia, and Photographs, circa 1948-2002 (Box 170)
  - Correspondence, Memorabilia, and Photographs, circa 1948-2002 (Box 171)
  - Correspondence, Memorabilia, and Photographs, circa 1948-2002 (Box 172)
  - Correspondence, Memorabilia, and Photographs, circa 1948-2002 (Box 173)
  - Loose Items from an unused Scrapbook, circa 1948 (Box 173)
  - Interview Transcripts, circa 1982 (Box 173)
  - Writings, circa 1950s-1980s (Box 173)
  - Notebook, 1974 (Box 173)
  - Book, The Complete Works of William Shakespeare, 1948 (Box 174)
  - Book, The Pentateuch and Haftorahs, undated (Box 174)
  - Yearbooks, 1951,1955 (Box 174)
  - Passports, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 174)
  - Day Planners and loose pages, circa 1970s (Box 174)
  - Memorial Service Guestbooks, 2002; (2 volumes) (Box 174)
  - Tribute to Holly, 2002 (Box 175)
  - Anthology Film Archives Benefit, 2002 (Box 175)
  - Holly's Finances, 2001 (Box 175)
  - Clippings on Holly, circa 1990s (Box 175)
  - Holly's Portrait Collection, 2001 (Box 175)
  - Holly's Book Information, 2001 (Box 175)
  - Inventory from Holly's Appartment (444), 1998 (Box 175)
  - Holly's Apartment, circa 1990s; (3 folders) (Box 175)
  - The EHL (Lauder) Collection, undated (Box 175)
  - Divorce and Legal Documents, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 176)
  - Divorce and Legal Documents, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 177)
  - Printed Material, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 178)
  - Printed Material, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 179)
  - Printed Material, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 180)
  - Printed Material, circa 1955-2002 (Box 181)
  - Printed Material, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 182)
  - Sarah Lawrence College Alumni Award Plaque, 2001 (Box 182)